SKYLAR LIANG

Phone: +1 (604) 652 7585 Email: skylar.liang233@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/skylar-liang/

Vancouver, BC, Canada

Profile

Third-year computer engineering student at the University of British Columbia with experience using major languages including Java, C, C++ and Python. Capable of working alone as well as in a group setting.

Technical Communication

Problem solving

Microsoft Office (Word, PPT, Excel)

Quick learning and self-teaching

Skills & Professional Development

Technical Skills

Java, C, C++, Python, JavaScript, SQL

- Django, Node.js, React Native
- MongoDB, MySQL

Courses/Training

- **UBC** safety training
- CPEN 321: Software Engineering

AWS (EC2, RDS), GCP

- Linux, Windows
- Android Studio
- Agile/Scrum

ELEC 331: Computer Networking

CPSC 304: Relational Database

Experience

Teaching Assistant – the University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC

Jan 2019 - Present

Teaching assistant for CPSC 261: Basics of Computer System

Computer Science Tutor – K&D Education Institute, Vancouver, BC

Jan 2018 - Jan 2019

Tutored courses in C and Java

Volunteer Engineer - WindAid Institute, Trujillo, Peru

July 2018

2016 - 2020

Collaborated with other volunteers from all over the world building and installing two wind turbines for a Peruvian village.

Education

The University of British Columbia - Vancouver, BC

Undergraduate in Computer engineering (bachelor's degree moving forward)

- Dean's Honor List (2018)
- Scholarships: outstanding international students' scholarship (2018); Trek Scholarship (2017)

Projects

Memory Frame - an electronic photo frame with voice control and an Android app

Mar 2019

- Group Project: Android, Firebase, Alexa, Raspberry Pi, Python
- Developed backend for communication between firebase and user ends (Java and Python)

Share Chore - an app for roommates to keep track of everyone's share on housework

Feb 2019

- Hackathon project: Android
- Co-developed frontend and backend with XML and Java
- Started with little Android development knowledge but learnt to use Android Studio and built a functional app with it in 24 hours

Store Way-finder - help specialty store customers to locate themselves and find items

Jan - Feb 2019

- Group Project: Raspberry Pi, Python, AWS, MySQL
- Back-end developer on database and Bluetooth communication using python
- Managed cloud database on AWS